<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>The Corollary Zone</title>
		<description>A collection of projects by Jim Hays</description>
		<link></link>
		<atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Super Sharp</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Lately I’ve been enjoing replaying through an iOS game that came out in 2015 called &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/super-sharp/id1033873301&quot;&gt;Super Sharp&lt;/a&gt;.  With a lot of lateral thinking, patience, and luck, I’ve been optimizing the levels to solve them with as few cuts as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/super-sharp/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/super-sharp/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Fruit Emoji Puzzle</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;For our child’s first birthday, we celebrated with a fruit-themed party!  Among other things, this included a fruit puzzle.  The objective is to identify the fruit from the emoji, which is my own contribution to the guess-the-thing-from-the-emoji genre of puzzle.  (Other entries in the genre include movies, children’s books, tv shows, Halloween candy, bands, and many more)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 02:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/fruit-emoji/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/fruit-emoji/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Puzzled Pint</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;I was the author of the most recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://puzzledpint.com/index.php?cID=1274&quot;&gt;Puzzled Pint set for July 2022&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/squid-game/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/squid-game/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Wormle</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Since &lt;em&gt;Baba is You&lt;/em&gt; has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://hempuli.itch.io/baba-is-you-level-editor-beta&quot;&gt;level editor&lt;/a&gt;, it seemed too good an opportunity to pass up making a version of Wordle in &lt;em&gt;Baba is You&lt;/em&gt;.  Unfortunately it’s a bit laggy.  Maybe someone else can find a different implementation that is more efficient, or dynamic (the answer to this puzzle is static).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/wormle/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/wormle/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Whodle</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;As a follow-up to &lt;a href=&quot;/wheredle&quot;&gt;Wheredle&lt;/a&gt;, I’ve also created &lt;a href=&quot;https://calvinballing.github.io/whodle/&quot;&gt;Whodle&lt;/a&gt;.  It uses the same rule set as Wordle but instead of guessing a five-letter word you guess a five-letter name.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/whodle-writeup/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/whodle-writeup/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Wheredle</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;With the Wordle craze in full bloom, I’ve decided to add my own contribution, &lt;a href=&quot;https://calvinballing.github.io/wheredle/&quot;&gt;Wheredle&lt;/a&gt;.  It’s effectively the same as Wordle still guessing a five-letter word using the same answer list and dictionary, except you also have to guess &lt;strong&gt;where&lt;/strong&gt; the word appears in a series of ten blanks. I also give one extra guess (7 instead of 6).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 02:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/wheredle-writeup/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/wheredle-writeup/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Super Baba Bros</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been playing around with &lt;em&gt;Baba is You&lt;/em&gt;’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://hempuli.itch.io/baba-is-you-level-editor-beta&quot;&gt;level editor&lt;/a&gt;, and decided to do a quarter-scale remake of &lt;em&gt;Super Mario Bros World 1-1&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/super-baba-bros/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/super-baba-bros/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Spoon or Rhythm</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Apropos of nothing, here is a puzzle I wrote:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/spoon-or-rhythm/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/spoon-or-rhythm/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Glass Stepping Stones Info&amp;shy;graphic</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;I made a Squid Game infographic showing the progress of the players across the Glass Stepping Stones throughout the episode&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 22:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/glass-stepping-stones/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/glass-stepping-stones/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Jelly Game</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been playing around with &lt;em&gt;Baba is You&lt;/em&gt;’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://hempuli.itch.io/baba-is-you-level-editor-beta&quot;&gt;level editor&lt;/a&gt;, and made a level set inspired by the show &lt;em&gt;Squid Game&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/jelly-game/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/jelly-game/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Multiplayer Online Games</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;With the pandemic, it’s nice to have some ways to connect with friends and family online.  Here are some free multiplayer online games you can check out:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/multiplayer-games/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/multiplayer-games/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>BotW Painting Recreations</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been enjoying playing the Switch game Breath of the Wild.  As a large, open world game, there are lots of possible things to do and to explore. This has led to a number of intersting ways to play the game such as this &lt;a href=&quot;https://michellewesterlaken.com/2017/05/24/breath-of-the-wild-vegan-run/&quot;&gt;vegan run&lt;/a&gt;.  Having played through the majority of the intended quests, I set out to make some of my own.  Here are some of the results of my attempt to recreate famous paintings inside of Breath of the Wild.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/botw-recreations/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/botw-recreations/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Photo Scavenger Hunts</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;An outdoor Social Distancing activity some of my housemates and I have been enjoying recently has been to go on photo scavenger hunts around the neighborhood.  For each one we’ve tried something a little different. My favorite so far is probably the Color Wheel Scavenger Hunt.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 19:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/scavenger/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/scavenger/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>X &amp; Z Creation Myths</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;When beginning &lt;a href=&quot;/saga&quot;&gt;Saga’s Start&lt;/a&gt;, a version of Genesis 1 using only words starting with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;S&lt;/code&gt;, I settled on &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; as it seemed like one of the easist letters to do, and something I could accomplish using the tools I had on hand, rather than needing to create awesome new tooling as Doug Summers-Stay did for &lt;a href=&quot;http://llamasandmystegosaurus.blogspot.com/2017/05/alpha.html&quot;&gt;ALPHA (A TRANSLATION OF GENESIS 1)&lt;/a&gt;.  Afterwards, I was wondering if it would be possible to do a version with a more constricting letter, so I took a crack at both X and Z.  It actually ended up being easier in some ways; with fewer options, many of the decisions are already made.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/x-z-genesis/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/x-z-genesis/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Saga&apos;s Start</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;1&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; So started saga: Supreme sentience shaped skies, secular sphere.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/saga/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/saga/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Isles of Agudas Achim</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve planted a new letterbox in Columbus!  The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atlasquest.com/boxes/clue/?boxId=312414&quot;&gt;clues are posted on AtlasQuest&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/agudas-achim/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/agudas-achim/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Everything is Information</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Hanabi is a cooperative firework-themed board game in which players collectively try to build five piles of cards representing five different colors of fireworks.  Each pile has to be all the same color, and has to start from &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;1&lt;/code&gt; and work up to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;5&lt;/code&gt;.  The twist is that each player holds their cards facing away from them so that every other player knows what they have, except the player holding those cards.  Turns consist of trying to play a card, discarding a card, or giving a hint to another player about their cards in a specified format (e.g. “Here are all your 3s” or “Here are all your green cards”).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 23:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/information/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/information/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Sampling Bias</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;If half of all cars on the road drive 60 miles per hours, and the other half drive 70, then then each driver will encounter one of two scenarios:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 23:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/sampling/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/sampling/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Instruments of Destruction</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;A short story in which Admiral Tian Jerjerrod tackles the impossible task of building the second Death Star, written by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fanfiction.net/s/11685932/1/Instruments-of-Destruction&quot;&gt;Alexander Wales&lt;/a&gt;, read by Jim Hays.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 15:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/destruction/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/destruction/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Non-Overlapping Visibility</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;What if a planet evolved distinct intelligent species with sensors designed for detecting non-overlapping portions of the electromagnetic spectrum as visible light?  Perhaps this would occur on a planet in a multi-star system where the stars are in different portions of their lifecycle and emit different colors of light, such as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Epsilon_Indi&quot;&gt;Epsilon Indi star system&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 05:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/visibility/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/visibility/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Metro&amp;shy;politan Man Cameo</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;I have a bit part playing the lead juror in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hpmorpodcast.com/wp-content/uploads/episodes/MM_Ep_13.mp3&quot;&gt;Chapter 13: A Vast and Terryifying Enemy: part 2&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hpmorpodcast.com/?page_id=1705&quot;&gt;audio production of The Metropolitan Man&lt;/a&gt;, produced by Eneasz Brodski. The story is originally written by Alexander Wales, and can be found on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fanfiction.net/s/10360716/1/The-Metropolitan-Man&quot;&gt;fanfiction.net&lt;/a&gt;.  This rationalist fiction wonders what might be going through the mind of Lex Luthor in the Metropolis Universe.  This would be interesting on its own, even if Lex were not a compelling rationalist figure, who invites the reader to consider whether they ought to feel morally compelled to pursue a course of action marking them as a ‘super-villan’.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 17:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/metropolitan/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/metropolitan/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Lord of the Rings as our Post-Apocalyptic Future</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;I’m not the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/Do-the-Lord-of-the-Rings-novels-and-films-take-place-in-a-post-apocalyptic-setting&quot;&gt;first&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://nerditis.com/2013/10/13/why-lord-of-the-rings-is-a-post-apocalyptic-wasteland/&quot;&gt;person&lt;/a&gt; to interpret the Lord of the Rings with an emphasis on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://patricksatters.blogspot.com/2013/05/lord-of-rings-and-other-fantasy-as-post.html&quot;&gt;post-apocalyptic&lt;/a&gt; nature.  However, I have not seen the story imagined as as taking place within our &lt;em&gt;own&lt;/em&gt; future, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Planet_of_the_Apes_(1968_film)&quot;&gt;Planet of the Apes&lt;/a&gt;-style. It’s plausible to construct a frame-story for the Lord of the Rings where the seemingly-magical/fantastic elements have scientific/sociological/technological explanations.  Let’s take a few of the specific cases.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 04:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/post-apocalyptic-LOTR/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/post-apocalyptic-LOTR/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Lonely Photo&amp;shy;grapher</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;A short story documenting a Lonely Photographer, written by &lt;a href=&quot;https://qntm.org/lonely&quot;&gt;Sam Hughes&lt;/a&gt;, read by Jim Hays&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 23:16:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/lonely-photographer/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/lonely-photographer/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Valuable Humans in Transit</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;A short story about a super-intelligent AI and imminent danger for humanity, written by &lt;a href=&quot;https://qntm.org/transit&quot;&gt;Sam Hughes&lt;/a&gt;, read by Jim Hays&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 18:57:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/valuable-humans/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/valuable-humans/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Jabber&amp;shy;wocky in Common Words</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;First there was &lt;a href=&quot;xkcd.com&quot;&gt;xkcd&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://xkcd.com/1133/&quot;&gt;Up Goer Five&lt;/a&gt; picture joke using only the ten Hundred words people say the most.  Then came the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.xkcd.com/2015/05/13/new-book-thing-explainer/&quot;&gt;Thing Explainer&lt;/a&gt; book. Eventually there was a &lt;a href=&quot;http://splasho.com/upgoer5/&quot;&gt;computer word checker&lt;/a&gt;.  My own take on using the computer word checker is farther down:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2015 22:26:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/jabberwocky/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/jabberwocky/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Greek to Me</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;In English, the expresion goes &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greek_to_me&quot;&gt;“It’s all Greek to me!”&lt;/a&gt;, but in Greek the expression is basically “It’s all Turkish to me!”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 12:49:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/inscrutability/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/inscrutability/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Ambigrams</title>
				
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;This is a display of rotationally symmetric &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ambigram&quot;&gt;ambigrams&lt;/a&gt; I’ve designed for various occasions.  I’ve repeatedly been surprised at ambigrammable word combinations that seemed unlikely or impossible at first blush.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2012 19:41:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>/ambigrams/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/ambigrams/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
